<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<modDesc descVersion="109">
    <author>Avolation Industries</author>
    <version>1.3.0.0</version>
    <title>
        <en>ModMixer</en>
    </title>
    <description>
        <en><![CDATA[
Mods silently break each other. When two mods change the same game function, the one that loads last usually wins — the other mod's work just vanishes: no error, no crash, no explanation. ModMixer finds these conflicts, explains them in plain English, and gives you a control panel to settle them.

THE SWITCHBOARD
A full control panel in the in-game menu (look for the ModMixer icon), seven tabs:
- SIMPLE — rank your mods; a higher mod wins its conflicts everywhere. All most setups ever need.
- LIVE — instant settings your mods expose (toggles and sliders), applied in-game immediately.
- CATEGORY — the same ranking, one area at a time: wheels, HUD, economy, weather...
- ADVANCED — every contested function with its full hook chain: who runs first, who overrides whom. Reorder the chain or mute a stomp, per conflict.
- REVIEW — worth a look: likely duplicate mods, known incompatible pairs, HUD overlaps — each with evidence. Dismiss what you've judged.
- PERFORMANCE — live per-mod cost (ms per frame) against your fps budget. Find the mod eating your frame rate and park it without uninstalling.
- VEHICLE — live diagnostics of the machine you're sitting in: damage, wear, temperature, speed, mass, per-wheel grip.

Every row comes with a plain-English explanation. You still get the classic boot conflict report (ModMixer.log, next to your game log) and an on-screen warning when two flatly incompatible mods are installed.

BUILT SAFE
- Structural changes (reorder, mute) apply on restart — nothing is rewired mid-game.
- Load-critical functions are locked and can never be vetoed.
- If a launch doesn't complete, the next one starts in safe mode automatically (all levers off) — your game always loads.
- Manual kill switch: create an empty file MODMIXER_SAFE_MODE.txt in modSettings/FS25_ModMixer/.

IMPORTANT: keep the zip named FS25_0_ModMixer.zip — the 0 makes it load before your other mods, which is how it sees every hook they install.

Multiplayer: loads and reports per client; the Switchboard's levers are designed for singleplayer.

Changelog 1.3.0.0:
- The Switchboard — the seven-tab control panel above
- Performance profiler with live per-mod frame cost and Park
- Review hub, vehicle diagnostics, and the boot-recovery safety net

GitHub:  https://github.com/AvolationIndustries/FS25_ModMixer
By Avolation Industries.
]]></en>
        <de><![CDATA[
Mods machen sich gegenseitig stillschweigend kaputt. Wenn zwei Mods dieselbe Spielfunktion verändern, gewinnt meist der zuletzt geladene – die Arbeit des anderen Mods verschwindet einfach: kein Fehler, kein Absturz, keine Erklärung. ModMixer findet diese Konflikte, erklärt sie in klaren Worten und gibt dir eine Schaltzentrale, um sie zu klären.

DAS SWITCHBOARD
Eine komplette Schaltzentrale im Ingame-Menü (achte auf das ModMixer-Symbol), sieben Reiter:
- SIMPLE – Sortiere deine Mods nach Rang; ein höher gesetzter Mod gewinnt seine Konflikte überall. Für die meisten Setups reicht das völlig.
- LIVE – Sofort-Einstellungen, die deine Mods anbieten (Schalter und Regler), wirken direkt im Spiel.
- CATEGORY – Dieselbe Rangfolge, Bereich für Bereich: Räder, HUD, Wirtschaft, Wetter ...
- ADVANCED – Jede umkämpfte Funktion mit ihrer kompletten Hook-Kette: wer zuerst läuft, wer wen überschreibt. Kette umsortieren oder ein Überschreiben stummschalten, pro Konflikt.
- REVIEW – Einen Blick wert: wahrscheinliche Mod-Dubletten, bekannte inkompatible Paare, HUD-Überlappungen – jeweils mit Belegen. Erledigtes lässt sich ausblenden.
- PERFORMANCE – Live-Kosten pro Mod (ms pro Frame) gegen dein FPS-Budget. Finde den Mod, der deine Framerate frisst, und parke ihn, ohne ihn zu deinstallieren.
- VEHICLE – Live-Diagnose der Maschine, in der du sitzt: Schaden, Verschleiß, Temperatur, Geschwindigkeit, Masse, Grip pro Rad.

Jede Zeile wird verständlich erklärt. Dazu gibt es weiterhin den Konfliktbericht beim Start (ModMixer.log, neben deinem Spiel-Log) und eine Bildschirmwarnung, wenn zwei wirklich inkompatible Mods installiert sind.

AUF SICHERHEIT GEBAUT
- Strukturelle Änderungen (Umsortieren, Stummschalten) greifen erst nach einem Neustart – nichts wird mitten im Spiel umverdrahtet.
- Ladekritische Funktionen sind gesperrt und können nie blockiert werden.
- Schlägt ein Start fehl, startet der nächste automatisch im abgesicherten Modus (alle Eingriffe aus) – dein Spiel lädt immer.
- Manueller Notschalter: lege eine leere Datei MODMIXER_SAFE_MODE.txt in modSettings/FS25_ModMixer/ an.

WICHTIG: Lass die Zip-Datei FS25_0_ModMixer.zip heißen – die 0 sorgt dafür, dass sie vor deinen anderen Mods lädt; nur so sieht ModMixer jeden Hook.

Multiplayer: lädt und berichtet pro Client; die Eingriffe des Switchboards sind für den Einzelspieler gedacht.

Changelog 1.3.0.0:
- Das Switchboard – die Schaltzentrale mit sieben Reitern
- Performance-Profiler mit Live-Kosten pro Mod und Parkfunktion
- Review-Hub, Fahrzeugdiagnose und das Sicherheitsnetz mit automatischer Boot-Wiederherstellung

GitHub:  https://github.com/AvolationIndustries/FS25_ModMixer
Von Avolation Industries.
]]></de>
        <fr><![CDATA[
Les mods se cassent mutuellement, en silence. Quand deux mods modifient la même fonction du jeu, c'est généralement le dernier chargé qui l'emporte – le travail de l'autre disparaît tout simplement : pas d'erreur, pas de plantage, pas d'explication. ModMixer détecte ces conflits, les explique clairement et vous donne un panneau de contrôle pour les régler.

LE SWITCHBOARD
Un panneau de contrôle complet dans le menu en jeu (cherchez l'icône ModMixer), sept onglets :
- SIMPLE – Classez vos mods ; un mod mieux classé gagne ses conflits partout. Suffit dans la plupart des cas.
- LIVE – Les réglages instantanés exposés par vos mods (interrupteurs et curseurs), appliqués immédiatement en jeu.
- CATEGORY – Le même classement, domaine par domaine : roues, HUD, économie, météo...
- ADVANCED – Chaque fonction disputée avec sa chaîne de hooks complète : qui s'exécute en premier, qui écrase qui. Réordonnez la chaîne ou coupez un écrasement, conflit par conflit.
- REVIEW – À examiner : doublons probables, paires incompatibles connues, chevauchements de HUD – preuves à l'appui. Masquez ce que vous avez tranché.
- PERFORMANCE – Coût par mod en direct (ms par image) face à votre budget FPS. Trouvez le mod qui dévore vos FPS et mettez-le en sommeil sans le désinstaller.
- VEHICLE – Diagnostic en direct de la machine que vous conduisez : dégâts, usure, température, vitesse, masse, adhérence roue par roue.

Chaque ligne est expliquée en langage clair. Vous conservez le rapport de conflits au démarrage (ModMixer.log, à côté du journal du jeu) et un avertissement à l'écran lorsque deux mods réellement incompatibles sont installés.

CONÇU POUR LA SÉCURITÉ
- Les changements structurels (réordonner, couper) ne s'appliquent qu'au redémarrage – rien n'est recâblé en pleine partie.
- Les fonctions critiques au chargement sont verrouillées et ne peuvent jamais être bloquées.
- Si un démarrage échoue, le suivant se lance automatiquement en mode sans échec (tous les leviers désactivés) – votre partie charge toujours.
- Coupe-circuit manuel : créez un fichier vide MODMIXER_SAFE_MODE.txt dans modSettings/FS25_ModMixer/.

IMPORTANT : conservez le nom FS25_0_ModMixer.zip – le 0 le fait charger avant vos autres mods ; c'est ainsi que ModMixer voit chaque hook.

Multijoueur : se charge et rapporte côté client ; les leviers du Switchboard sont conçus pour le solo.

Changelog 1.3.0.0:
- Le Switchboard – le panneau de contrôle à sept onglets
- Profileur de performance avec coût par mod en direct et mise en sommeil
- Hub Review, diagnostic véhicule et filet de sécurité avec récupération automatique au démarrage

GitHub :  https://github.com/AvolationIndustries/FS25_ModMixer
Par Avolation Industries.
]]></fr>
    </description>
    <iconFilename>icon_ModMixer.dds</iconFilename>
    <multiplayer supported="true"/>

    <!-- Action display names (kills the "Missing l10n input_ModMixer_SB_*" boot warnings;
         these are what Settings > Controls shows for each binding). -->
    <l10n>
        <text name="input_ModMixer_SB_FILTER_PREV">
            <en>ModMixer: previous category</en>
            <de>ModMixer: vorherige Kategorie</de>
            <fr>ModMixer : catégorie précédente</fr>
        </text>
        <text name="input_ModMixer_SB_FILTER_NEXT">
            <en>ModMixer: next category</en>
            <de>ModMixer: nächste Kategorie</de>
            <fr>ModMixer : catégorie suivante</fr>
        </text>
        <text name="input_ModMixer_SB_MOVE_EARLIER">
            <en>ModMixer: move hook earlier</en>
            <de>ModMixer: Hook nach vorne schieben</de>
            <fr>ModMixer : avancer le hook</fr>
        </text>
        <text name="input_ModMixer_SB_MOVE_LATER">
            <en>ModMixer: move hook later</en>
            <de>ModMixer: Hook nach hinten schieben</de>
            <fr>ModMixer : reculer le hook</fr>
        </text>
        <text name="input_ModMixer_SB_RESET_ONE">
            <en>ModMixer: reset row</en>
            <de>ModMixer: Zeile zurücksetzen</de>
            <fr>ModMixer : réinitialiser la ligne</fr>
        </text>
        <text name="input_ModMixer_SB_RESET_PAGE">
            <en>ModMixer: reset page</en>
            <de>ModMixer: Seite zurücksetzen</de>
            <fr>ModMixer : réinitialiser la page</fr>
        </text>
        <text name="input_ModMixer_SB_RESET_ALL">
            <en>ModMixer: reset all</en>
            <de>ModMixer: alles zurücksetzen</de>
            <fr>ModMixer : tout réinitialiser</fr>
        </text>
    </l10n>

    <!-- Custom input actions for the Switchboard in-game page.
         No default bindings here — they appear in Settings > Controls under "Other"
         so the player can assign whatever keys work for their layout.
         The on-screen action bar shows the actual assigned key once bound. -->
    <actions>
        <action name="ModMixer_SB_FILTER_PREV" />
        <action name="ModMixer_SB_FILTER_NEXT" />
        <action name="ModMixer_SB_MOVE_EARLIER" />
        <action name="ModMixer_SB_MOVE_LATER" />
        <action name="ModMixer_SB_RESET_ONE" />
        <action name="ModMixer_SB_RESET_PAGE" />
        <action name="ModMixer_SB_RESET_ALL" />
    </actions>
    <inputBinding>
        <!-- Filter + move: no defaults — player assigns in Settings > Controls.
             Three-tier reset (escalating scope, all on Backspace):
               Reset row  = Backspace          (selected row back to default)
               Reset page = Ctrl+Backspace     (current category)
               Reset all  = Shift+Backspace    (everything)
             EV-style format: multi-key combos use space-separated input attr. -->
        <actionBinding action="ModMixer_SB_RESET_ONE">
            <binding device="KB_MOUSE_DEFAULT" input="KEY_backspace" axisComponent="+" inputComponent="+" index="1"/>
        </actionBinding>
        <actionBinding action="ModMixer_SB_RESET_PAGE">
            <binding device="KB_MOUSE_DEFAULT" input="KEY_lctrl KEY_backspace" axisComponent="+" inputComponent="+" index="1"/>
            <binding device="KB_MOUSE_DEFAULT" input="KEY_rctrl KEY_backspace" axisComponent="+" inputComponent="+" index="1"/>
        </actionBinding>
        <actionBinding action="ModMixer_SB_RESET_ALL">
            <binding device="KB_MOUSE_DEFAULT" input="KEY_lshift KEY_backspace" axisComponent="+" inputComponent="+" index="1"/>
            <binding device="KB_MOUSE_DEFAULT" input="KEY_rshift KEY_backspace" axisComponent="+" inputComponent="+" index="1"/>
        </actionBinding>
    </inputBinding>

    <extraSourceFiles>
        <sourceFile filename="scripts/ModMixerHooks.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="scripts/mm_catalogue_generated.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="scripts/mm_hookmap_generated.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="scripts/mm_redundancy_generated.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="scripts/ModMixer.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="scripts/Switchboard.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="gui/SwitchboardFrame.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="gui/SwitchboardMenu.lua"/>
    </extraSourceFiles>
</modDesc>
